Mss.Ms.Coll.200
American Philosophical Society
- Papers
  - Letter to Amram Scheinfeld, New York, May 12, 1947; Muller, H. J., (Hermann Joseph), 1890-1967
    T.L.S. 1p. Thanks for "Liberty" article. Discusses genetic effects of radiation.
  - The Hillegas family in Europe and early America, Oct., 1947; Schell, Jack Stewart
    Typed D. 17p. Presented by Mrs. Edward Newlands; through Aaron R. Coleman, U.S. Consul in Vancover, B.C.; Dec. 1969.
  - The pictorial reconstruction of Franklin's Fort Allen, November 24, 1947; 8 1/2" x 11" 22 1/2" x 14"; McConomy, John A.
    T.D.S. [1] 27p.map, 3pl. Presented by the author, Nov. 1947.
    - Site of Fort Allen, Pennsylvania, 1947 November 24; 1 map, 22.9 x 20.3 cm; McConomy, John A.
      Identifies Old Fort Allen, built by Benjamin Franklin, at Gnadenhuetten in 1756. McConomy says his identification is the "probable site" on Franklin and Allen Streets, near the Lehigh River in the "n.w. corner Weissport Borough." This map accompanies a sketch of the fort and an article on the fort by Rev. John A. McConomy.
      Realms of Gold, 33 (9).
  - Eugene A. Vail, [1947]
    Typed D. 5p. "Compiled ... from the Aaron Vail papers [New York State Library, Albany]". Presented by Dr. Gilbert Chinard, Feb. 1947.
  - Bilbliography of George Grant MacCurdy, Jan. 24, 1948; MacCurdy, George Grant, 1863-1947
    Copy of T.D. 13p.
  - Analysis of documents on Baron de Beelen Bertholff, Jan., 1948; 8 1/2" x 13"; Dorlodot, Albert de
    his mission in America, his life there and his children, Mimeo. D.S. 7 leaves Contains letter, Feb. 17,1948 explaining study.
  - Concerning the ships named Franklin in the U.S. Navy, July 3, 1948; 12-1/2x8; Hamilton, Harry D.
    A.D.S. 5p. FILM54-67-FRAME54
  - The Cree Indians' Theology, Oct. 1, 1948; 11x8-1/2; Ahenakew, Edward
    A.D.S. 5p. Presented by P.A.W.Wallace; 1948.
  - Letter to Henry [Butler Allen], Feb. 3, 1949; 11x8-1/2:7x6; Van Doren, Carl, 1885-1950
    New York, Typed L.S. 1p.and 2p.enc. B.Franklin's rum punch. Encloses copy of poem [original in Am.Ant.Soc.]by B. Franklin, the uncle. Poem printed:Van Doren: Franklin-Mecom, pp.348-350. Presented by H.V.Bail; Dec.1962.
  - Don Ricardo Shryock, June 2, 1949; 11x8-1/2; Whitaker, Arthur Preston, 1895-1979
    Latin Americanist; Typed D.S. 3p. Presented by Dr. Shryock; Dec. 1962.
  - Letter to the Pennsylvania historic society, Nov. 20, 1949; Ramsden, Josslyn
    Devon, Photostat of T.L. 1p. and enc. -6p. Encloses some genealogical material about the Franklin family from the Parish registers of the Parishes of offwell and Widworthy. Presented by the Historical society of Pennsylvania, Dec. 1949.
  - Letters concerning "The hatchability of chicken eggs....", 1949-1952
    T.L.S. 4 pcs. Various sizes. Letters from John F. Fulton, George Sarton Seabury Colum Gilfillan (in phonetic alphabet), and Mario Gilozzi (in Ital.) in re Landauer's "The Hatchability of chicken Eggs as Influenced by Environment & heredity ." 1948. Mentions Giambattista dalla Porta, immorality of "biologic inventions, " Isis.
  - Misc. manuscripts concerning Pliny Earle Goddard, 1949-1973; Goddard, David R.
    D. 15p. Includes corresp. regarding use of P.E. Goddard material by George W. Stocking and John Collier; partial lists of P.E. Goddard publications; acecdote about Franz Boas from Stefansson autobigraphy.
  - Letter to O[liver] H[azard] Perry Pepper, Feb. 13, 1950; 11x8-1/2; Conklin, Edwin Grant, 1863-1952
    Princeton, A.L.S. 1p. Thanks for his book on medicine. Comments on it. Presented by Dr. Pepper; 5/29/61.
  - Letter to Mrs. Anna Lane Lingelbach, Phila., April 5, 1950; International Rescue Committee.
    New York, Typed L.S.: Richard E. Byrd. 1p., enc. wanting. An appeal for financial support to save the men and women in Soviet concentration camps. On Iron Curtain Refugee Campaign letterhead.
  - Letter to H[antaro] Nagaoka, Tokyo, July 20, 1950; 10x7-1/4; Lawrence, Ernest Orlando, 1901-1958
    Berkeley Cal., Typed L.S. 1p. Xerox copy. Concerning his son, Ryokichi and his stay in the United States. Friendly letter. Presented by Dr. Eri Yogi, Tokyo University; June 1965.
  - Letter to Prof. [Edwin G.] Conklin, Sept. 24, 1950; 6 1/2" x 10"; Broom, Robert, 1866-1951
    Transvaal museum, Pretoria, S.A., A.L.S. 3p.,il. Ancestors of man. Presented by Dr. Conklin, Oct. 1950.
  - Letter to Dr. H. D. Smyth, U.S. Atomic Energy Commission, Nov. 1, 1950; Oppenheimer, J. Robert, 1904-1967
    Los Alamos Scientiic Laboratory. T.D.S: J. R. Oppenheimer, et. al. 1p. Comments on pleasent visit. Instructs Smyth that the salary scale for new posotion is too low for the job, and raising it will be necessary to compete with industry. "We feel especially that the present salary of the Director of the Laboratory is wholly inadequate and should be substatially increaded."
  - Letter to Dr. [Edwin G.] Conklin], Dec. 2, 1950; 6 1/2" x 10"; Broom, Robert, 1866-1951
    Transvaal museum, Pretoria, S.A., A.L.S. 4p. Ancestors of man. Presented by Dr. Conklin,Dec.1950.
  - Letter to [Harlow] Shapley, Dec. 10, 1950
  - List of photographs taken April,May and June, 1950; 13x8; Barbeau, Marius, 1883-1969
    in his research on whalers and clipper ship activities in the Pacific and Arctic Oceans from 1785 to 1860; 1950. Typed D. 64p. Carbon copy.
  - Delivered at St. John's church, 1950; 8 1/2" x 11"; Meade, Robert Douthat, 1903-1974
    Richmond on the one hundred seventy-fifth anniversary of Patrick Henry's "Give me liberty..." Speech,1950. Grant material - filled with regular collections.
  - Tlingit materials, 1950-1954; 11x8-1/2; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004
    Typed D. 18p. Goes with Record 15. Presented by author; June 1962. Printed in part: BAE.Bul., 172, pp. 169-171.
  - Letter to Prof. [Edwin G.] Conklin., Jan., 1951; See, T. J. J. (Thomas Jefferson Jackson), b. 1866
    [ca.]. A.N.S. on calling card Death of his wife. Biography of Laplace. Presented by Dr. Conklin, Jan.1951.
  - Letter to Henry W. Miller, Ann Arbor, Mich., April 29, 1951; 3-1/2x5-1/2; Hobbs, William Herbert, 1864-1952
    A.L.S. 1p.on postal card. Sorry he has been ill. Goes to do his work tomorrow. Located in: B:H655e. W.H.Hobbs. An Explorer Scientist's Pilgrimage.
  - Letter to T[homas] D. Cope, Wayne, Penna., May 22, 1951; 9x6; Bennett, P. W.
    Gloucester, Md., Photo.of Typed L.S. 1p. Thanks for pamphlet on the Mason-Dixon line. Presented by Dr. Cope, 1951.
  - Papers-description of collection in L.C., Aug. 13, 1951; Merriam, John C., (John Campbell), 1869-1945
    14 pages. Copy of finding aid.
  - Letter to Jane Oppenheimer, Sept. 27, 1951; 11x8-1/2; Goldschmidt, Richard, 1878-1958
    Berkeley, Calif., A.L.S. 1p. Hopes to visit her and hear of her experiences. Presented by J.Oppenheimer, April 4, 1967.
  - List of Moravian manuscripts from documents in the Moravian Archives, Bethlehem, 1951; 11x8-1/2; Pennsylvania Historical and Museum Commission
    [ca.]. Photo.of Typed D.and D. 12p.photo.and 1p.autograph.
  - The pemberton family cemetery, 1951; 8 1/2" x 11"; Witthoft, John
    Typed D. (c.c.) [1]14 [3] leaves, il. Presented by author, April 1951.
  - Studies on the action of uranium nitrate., 1951; 8 1/2" x 11"; MacNider, William de Berniere, 1881-1951
    Typed D.S. (c.c.) 4 leaves Bibliography. Presented by the author, 1951.
  - Letter to Mrs. [Gertrude D.] Hess, Jan. 16, 1952; 11x8; Litchfield, Dorothy Hale
    Types L. 1p. Quotes extract from book about Benjamin Franklin. Printed: Esther Warner, New Song in a Strange Land, p. 93-94.
  - Letter to Jane Oppenheimer, May 28, 1952; 11/x8-1/2; Goldschmidt, Richard, 1878-1958
    Calif., A.L.S. 2p. Enjoyed visiting her and seeing Bryn Mawr. Also, the Cezenne exhibit in New York. Presented by Jane Oppenheimer, April 4, 1967.
  - Ethno history:, 1952; 10-1/2x8; Snyderman, George Simon, 1908-
    Amalgam of anthrpology and history: [ca.]. Typed D. 19p. Concerning the interest of the APS in the American Indian.
  - Letter to Norman B. Torrey, New York, Jan. 19, 1953; 11x8-1/2; Watts, George B.
    Typed L. 2p. Carbon copy. Concerning a study of various editions of the Encyclopédie. Presented by Gilbert Chinard;Oct.1961.
  - Letter to Gilbert Chinard, Princeton, Feb. 2, 1953; 11x8-1/2; Watts, George B.
    Typed L.S. 1p. Concerning s study of various editions of the Encyclopédie. Presented by Gilbert Chinard; Oct.1961.
  - A preliminary listing of resources in American Indian languages in the Archives room, Nov. 1, 1953; 10 1/2" x 8"; Bethlehem (Pa.). Moravian Church
    as of, prepared by John Witthoft. Typed draft of D. 20p. Presented by Dr. Witthoft, June 1954.
  - Correspondence pertaining to passport difficulties, 1953; 11x8-1/2; Dunn, L. C. (Leslie Clarence), 1893-1974
    Typed D. 20p. Carbon copy. Presented by Dr. Dunn; 1966. UNRESTRICTED.
  - Benjamin Franklin's fingerprints, 1953-1954; 11" x 8 1/2"; Wallace, Paul A. W.
    ca. Dr. of T.D. with ms. revisions S. 22p. "Franklin in touch, not with the princes and prelates, but with Indians, prisoners ..."
  - Letter to Jane Oppenheimer, July 22, 1954; 11x8-1/2; Goldschmidt, Richard, 1878-1958
    Berkeley, Calif., A.L.S. 2p. Concerning Mangold and other artists. His health. His book on genetics. Family news. Presented by Jane Oppenheimer, April 4, 1967.
  - Addresses given over the Trans-Canada network of the Canadian broadcasting corp., Sept. 7,14,21, 1954; 11" x 8 1/2"; Leland, Marine
    T.D's 3pieces 1. Sept. 7 Indian captivity of Warham Williams, featuring Mme de Repentigny. 2. Sept. 14 Indian captivities, from Journal of Capt. John Stoddard.
  - George Harrison Shull, by E. Newton Harvey, A.K. Parpart, Luther P. Eisenhart, Nov. 1, 1954; Harvey, E. Newton (Edmund Newton), 1887-1959
    Memorial minute read at the meeting of the Princeton university faculty,Nov.1, 1954. Presented by Dr. Eisenhart, 1954.
  - K.F. Rul'e biologist-materialist of the first half of the nineteenth century, 1954; 11" x 8 1/2"; Mikulinskiĭ, S. R.
    tr. by Henry N. Michael Typed D. [1]14 leaves. 2 copies From Voprosy filosofii, 3(11),1950-155-172.
  - Letter to Frank Pleadwell, Honolulu, Hawaii, March 10, 1955; 11x8-1/2; Babb, James T. (James Tinkham), 1899-1968
    New Haven, Typed L.S. 1p. Concerning the purchase, and failure to purchase, of certain Franklin items. Refers to W.S.Mason.
  - Letter to E.T. Carvill, Deerfield, Ill., Aug. 25, 1955; 11" x 8 1/2"; Manion, Blanche H.
    Henderson, Ky., Photostat of T.L.S. 1p. Description of Audubon Memorial Museum at Henderson, Ky., of which she is curator.
  - Letter to W.W. McCullough, West Chester, Pa., Sept. 7, 1955; Paramount Pictures Corporation
    Hollywood, Reproduction of T.L.S.: Helen Gladys Percey. 1p. No known portraits of Charles Mason and Jeremiah Dixon. Presented by Dr. Thomas D. Cope,1956.
  - Notes on the grave of William Temple Franklin and his wife, on map of cimitière du Père Lachaise, Nov. 5, 1955; 11-3/4x10-3/4, 3-1/2x4; Bell, Whitfield J. (Whitfield Jenks)
    A.D.S.with initials. 2p.and map and note showing location of grave site. Presented by W.J.Bell, Jr., Dec. 1961.
  - Letter to Frank Stick, Kitty Hawk,N.C., Nov. 17, 1955; 10-1/2x8; Mead, Giles Willis, 1928-
    Typed L. 5p. Carbon copy. Concerning a manuscript on fishes of Pennsylvania, by Jacob Stauffer. For manuscript, see: J.Stauffer. Classification...family...of fish; ca. 1866-1879. (597:St25).
  - Some articles published recently on the Baltimore-Penn boundary surveys, 1955; 11" x 8 1/2"; Cope, Thomas D. (Thomas Darlington)
    T.D. 3 leaves Presented by the author,1955.
  - Concerning A. F. Blakeslee and the origin of genetics, 1955; Lederberg, Joshua
    Xerox of printed D. 2p. Presentd by J. Lederberg, Sept., 1974.
  - Adam Seybert (1733-1825), [1955]; 11" x 8 1/2"; Roney, Grady
    by Grady Roney and J. Hampton Hoch T.D. (c.c.) S: J. Hampton Hoch 1 15 1p. Paper read before the Section on historical pharmacy, American pharmaceutical association in convention, Miami, Fla., May 6, 1955. Presented by Mr Hoch, Aug. 1955.
  - Benjamin Franklin - natural philosopher., Jan. 16, 1956; 10" x 8"; Wightman, W. P. D. (William Persehouse Delisle)
    Typed D. with ms. corrections 10 leaves Address given at the Franklin commemoration meeting, Royal society of Edinburgh. Presented by the Royal society, March 1956.
  - Benjamin Franklin Englishman., April 26, 1956; 11" x 8 1/2"; Bell, Whitfield J. (Whitfield Jenks)
    T.D. 9 leaves. Remarks at a luncheon of the English speaking union. Presented by the author, May 1956.
  - Franklin descendants, Dec., 1956; 11" x 8 1/2"; Bell, Whitfield J. (Whitfield Jenks)
    T.D. 2p.
  - Mrs. Johnson's narrative of her captivity, Dec.-Jan., 1956-1957; 11" x 8 1/2"; Leland, Marine
    Typed D. Pt.1-3 Canadian broadcasting corp., Talks and public affairs, Speaker's Choice, Dec. 29, 1956, Jan.5, 12,1957. Presented by the author, Jan. 1957.
  - Songs by Willie Catfish, transcribed from tapes (see Rec. 75), 1956; 11x8-1/2; Kurath, Gertrude Prokosch
    Typed D.with sheet music. 8p.
  - Letter to Jane Oppenheimer, Sept. 19, 1957; 11x8-1/2; Goldschmidt, Richard, 1878-1958
    Berkeley, Calif., A.L.S. 2p. Concerning Suzuki's article, but "I have no organs for mysticism." Genetics. Comments on old age: "To hell with it!" Presented by Jane Oppenheimer, April 4, 1967.
  - Letter to Alexander Hollaender, Oak Ridge, Tenn., Oct. 10, 1957; Kaufmann, B. P., (Berwind Peterson), 1897-1975
    T.L. 1p. Plans to visit Hollaender. Refers to his schedule and work. Mentions genetics work of Sengun and Woods at Brookhaven. Refers to National Academy of Sciences, Rockefeller Institute.
  - Leidy material deposited at the College of Physicians of Philadelphia, 1957; 11" x 8 1/2"; Leidy, Joseph, 1823-1891
    comp. by D.H. Wenrich,1957. T.D. (c.c.) [52] leaves Contents: List of letters...relating to Dr. Joseph Leidy; Correspondence...of Dr. Joseph Leidy II; Miscellaneous biographical items relating to Prof. Joseph Leidy. Grant material; presented by the compiler, 1957.
  - Letter to Walter Landauer, Storrs, CT., Feb. 10, 1958; Popp, Olaf
    T.L.S. 1p. add. Thanks for reprints. Has read papers by Duraiswami. Questions on congenital abnormalities caused by insulin. Also: c.c. of Landauer's replay, Feb. 17, 1958.
  - Letter to Carl P. Russell, March 13, 1958; 11x8-1/2; Anderson, James
    Kansas City, Typed L. 2p. Copy. Concerning the location of Clark's Diary to make a treaty with the Osage Indians. Concerning the location of additional Clark items dealing with Fort Osage. For Diary see 917.3:Or2.
  - Checklist [compiled by Sanborn C. Brown], March, 1958; 11x8-1/2; Rumford, Benjamin, Graf von, 1753-1814
    Typed D. 41p. For report on this project, see 1957 yearbook of the APS.
  - Letter to [Edmund] Newton Harvey, Woods Hole, Mass., Sept. 2, 1958; 8x5; Huxley, Julian, 1887-1975
    London, A.L.S. 3p.and add. Enc. Friendly letter. Sends pamphlet. For pamphlet, see: Huxley. Emergence of Darwinism (575: Pam., no.32.) Presented by E.N.Harvey; Dec. 1958.
  - Letter to Warren R. Howell, Sept. 13, 1958; Haineback, Hans
    T.L. 1p. Thanks Howell for the two-volume "Cook's Voyage" by George Forsters. Says this handsome edition makes a good ending to the story of Haineback's "disappointment of not finding the George Forster- Sir Joseph Banks correspondence". Discusses other publications concerning Forester.
  - Bibliography, 1958-1975; Dvoĭchenko-Markova, E. M.
    Xerox of typed D. 14p. Inscribed by the author of the Library. In Russian. Presented by Demetrius Dvoichenko-Markov, Jun 18, 1976.
  - Letter to [Gilbert Chinard], Jan. 16, 1959; 10-3/4x8-1/2; Martin-Boutin, Mme
    Paris, Photo.of A.L.S. 2p. In french. Pertaining to her portrait of Franklin. Presented by G.Chinard; 1959.
  - Letter to [Berwin Petersen] Kaufmann, Feb. 13, 1959; Edwards, Joseph
    Thames Ditton, Eng. A.L.S. 1p. Sendy copy of book Breeding 10,000,000 cattle.
  - Letter to Chester Kerr, New Haven, Nov. 24, 1959; 11x8-1/2; Truman, Harry S., 1884-1972
    Independence, Mo., Photostat of typed L.S. 1p. Is sorry he cannot be in Philadelphia for the first volume presentation of The Papers of Benjamin Franklin. Presented by Mr. Kerr; Nov.1959.
  - Index (temporary) to microfilm of the Papers of the Continental congress, Dec., 1959; 10-1/2x8; United States. Continental Congress
    []. Typescript. 36p. Presented by National Park Service, Dec.1959.
  - Letter to Mrs. Gertrude D. Hess, Philadelphia, March 11, 1960; 11x8-1/2; Bell, Whitfield J. (Whitfield Jenks)
    New Haven, Typed L.S. 1p. Concerning extracts from Archibald Kennedy's Serious advice to the inhabitants of the northern colonies...1755, which are to be found in the Franklin Papers.
  - Letter to J[ohn A.] Moore, New York, March 11, 1960; Haldane, J. B. S. (John Burdon Sanderson), 1892-1964
    Calcutta, Typed L.S. 2p. Concerning Dronamraju and genetics. Refers to Dobzhansky. Presented by John A. Moore; Dec. 10, 1970.
  - Preface to his 1961 edition of The Special Theory of Relativity, Oct., 1960; Dingle, Herbert
    A.D.S. 5p. Concerns relativity, problems with Einstein's theories. Mentions Lorentz, Poincare, Ritz and Whitaker.
  - Letter to [Curt] Stern, Nov. 3, 1960; 12-1/2x8-1/2; Mohr, Otto Lous, 1886-
    Xerox of A.L.S. 2p. Genetics questions and comments. Wants help. Presented by Curt Stern; 1968.
    Not Found: 3/4/2011
  - "The Faith of a Humanist", [1960]; Huxley, Julian, 1887-1975
    Mimeograph. 4p. Essay on humanism, religion, ethics and progress in the modern, scientific age. Accompanied by a full signature and date (1960) on mounted card.
  - Private universities and the new unity of learning., May 3, 1961; 11x8-1/2; Weaver, Warren, 1894-1978
    Address given at the inauguration dinner in honor of Chancellor and Mrs. George Wells Beadle; Typed D. 17p. Presented by George W. Corner; Oct. 1964.
  - Letter to Eugeniusz Chudzicki, Poznan, July 26, 1961; Haxel, Otto
    Heidelberg, Typed L.S. 2p. In German. Concerning basic research in physics in pre-War Germany.
  - Letter to Eugeniusz Chudzicki, Poznan, Aug. 31, 1961; Pose, H.
    Dresden, Typed L.S. 2p. In German. Concerning the development of nuclear physics in Germany, and atonic energy after the war.
  - The American philosophical society and Audubon's "The Birds of America", 1961; 11x8-1/2; Fries, Waldemar H., b. 1889
    Typed D.. 10p. Presented by Fries; 1961.
  - Concerning Philip Tidyman of Charleston South Carolina, Aug. 20, 1962; 11x8-1/2; Davidson, Chalmers Gaston, 1907-1994
    Typed D. 1p. Copy.
  - Letter to Arthur --, [Dec. 25], 1962; Guthrie, Douglas, 1885-1975
    A.L.S. 2p. and encl. Sends copy of his history of the Royal Society Club. Personal news. Encloses information on history of medicine in Edinburgh.
  - Winnebago texts., [1962]; 4x6; Fraenkel, Gerd
    Notes to accompany Record 29; Typed D. 38 cards. Presented by compiler, Phillips grantee June 1962.
  - Letter to Antonio Pace, Syracuse, N.Y., April 2, [1963?]; 11-1/4x9; Panella, Silvia
    Typed L.S. 1p. Presents a copy of his thesis, Benjamin Franklin writer and humanist, and explains his interest in Franklin. (for thesis, see: B:F85.p.)
  - Description of stencils and specimen sheet of Franklin's Passy Press items..., April, 1963; 7-1/2x9-1/2; Conkwright, P. J. (P. Jefferson)
    A.D. 1p.and end. Presented by Howard Rice; May 17, 1963. For specimen sheet, see: B:F85.93; this was exhibited at Princeton at exhibition in honor of Conk wright.
  - Lick Observatory - the First 75 Years, June 27, 1963; 11x8-1/2; Shane, Charles Donald, 1895-
    Typed D. 9p. Presented by Dr.Shane; Jan. 21, 1965.
  - Letter to Bert James Loewenberg, Bronxville, New York, Sept. 26, 1963; Dobson, Jessie
    Typed L.S. 1p. Sends biography of William Clift and hopes he has a pleasant journey home.
  - A Guide to his papers in the National Library of Australia, 1963; 10x8; Banks, Joseph, 1743-1820
    Typed D. 21p. This is to be used in connection with Film: Hist.of Science, No.3.2. Folder empty. See Table of Contents to Film 1139.1.
  - The eighteenth-century craftsmen of the St. Andrew's Society of Philadelphia, 1963; 11x8-1/2; Spawn, Willman
    Photo.of Typed D. 25p. Read at the Society's annual meeting; Oct. 30, 1963. Presented by the author, March 1964.
  - Work sheets on Philadelphia architecture:, 1963; 11x8-1/2; Teitelman, Edward
    a tentative listing of structures of architectural interest dating from 1820 to the present; 1963. Photodup.typed manuscript. 66p. Presented by the author; May 1964.
  - Concerning James Lick and the Lick Observatory, [1964]; 11x8-1/2; Shane, Charles Donald, 1895-
    Typed D. 22p. Copy. Reproduced with permission on Dr. Shane, Feb. 1965.
  - Paul Hindemith, 1964; 8-1/2x11; Lam, George
    Typed D., D. 43p. Printed obituary in Year Book, pp.164-170 (1965). Presented by George L. Lam, 1964.
  - On Galileo's philosophy of science - in retrospect, Sept. 16, 1964; 8x10-1/2; Seeger, Raymond John, 1906-
    Typed D. 61p. Presented by R. H. Shryock; Jan. 1966.
  - Reminiscences..., [1964?]; 11x8-1/2; Fowler, Henri W., 1878-1965
    Typed D. 25p. Xerox copies.
  - Mason and Dixon:, [1964]; 10-1/2x8; Mason, A. Hughlett
    Their Line and its Legend; Typed D.by A.Hughlett Mason and William F. Swindler. 34p. Carbon copy. Printed: American Heritage, vol. 15, no. 2, 22-29. Presented by grantees; April 1964.
  - Mason and Dixon, their line and its legend, by A. Hughlett Mason and William F[inley] Swindler, [1964]; 11x8-1/2; Mason, A. Hughlett
    Photo.of typed D. 33p. Printed [heavily edited]: American Heritage, vol. 15, no.2, 22-29,93-96.
  - Genealogical data of John Rush, ancestor of Benjamin Rush, Feb., 1965; 13x8; Rush, A. R.
    Typed D. 9p. Presented by A. R. Rush; March 1965.
  - Letter to B.J. Lowenberg, New Haven, Conn., June 23, 1965; Dobson, Jessie
    Typed A.L. 1p. Thanks for books on Darwin. Concerning Down House.
  - The Franklin-Dumas code and cipher, Oct., 1965; 11x8-1/2; Weingast, Marvin
    Typed D. 5p.with 2p.letter. Presented by the author; Oct. 1965.
  - Benjamin Franklin Printer-Publisher, March 15, 1966; 11x8-1/2; Miller, C. William (Clarence William), 1914-
    Typed D. 14p. Xerox copy. Presented by the author; March 1966.
  - The History of Radioactivity, June 15, 1966; 10x8; Badash, Lawrence
    Typed D. 13p.
  - Quelques notes supplementaires sur Pierre-Etienne DuPonceau, [1966]; 11x8-1/2; Coulet du Gard, René
    Xerox copy of typed carbon. 4p. This was published in: Bulletin de 1'Association des Amis de 1'Ile de Re, 1966.
  - Letter to R[aymond] T. Birge, Berkeley, Cal., Jan. 9, 1967; 11x8-1/2; Condon, Edward Uhler, 1902-1974
    Boulder, Col., Xerox copy of typed L.S. 9p. Concerning Birge's history of the Physics Department of the University of California.
  - Letter to philip J. Klass, March 20, April 6, 1967; Drabier, Jacques
    Hollywood. T.L.S. 2p. With reply of Klass, March 27. Concerns UFO's and the purported extra-terrestrial origin of Wesley and JoNell Bateman.
  - Letter to Berwind [Petersen] Kaufmann, May 12, 1967; McElree, Helen
    T.L.S. 1p add. Kaufmann's answer to McElree, 1p. n.d. Intereted in work of Chevreont and Kaufmann's researches. For use in virological studies. Concerns cytology, bio-chemistry.
  - Letter to the Franklin Institute, July 3, 1967; 8x5; White, Irene
    London, Eng., Photo.of A.L.S. 3p.with 3 photos. (from original in the Franklin Institute.) Owns lodestone, once property of B.Franklin. Presented by Joseph Hepburn, July 1967.
  - Biographical account of Irving Widmer Bailey, 1967; Sinnott, Edmund W. (Edmund Ware), 1888-1958
    D.S. 33L. Various sizes. Presented by Mrs. Edmund W. Sinnott; 1968.
  - Descripción del Abipon, 1967; 13-1/2x8-1/2; Najlis, Elena L.
    Typed D. 41p. In Spanish. Forwarded in letter to Carl F. Voegelin. Presented by Carl F. Voegelin; 1967.
  - Letter to Whitfield J. Bell, Jr., Philadelphia, 1967; Salter, Leon J.
    Typed L.S. 15p. Concerning medicine, Charles Conrad Abbott, James H. Means, vital statistics, etc.